healthpost.co.nz 2018-12-21

# Online Privacy & Security Policy | HealthPost NZ

**Date Last Updated:** 5th June 2018

---|---  
  
## The Short Version

**We value your privacy and make it a priority to safeguard your personal information.**

******We do not sell or rent your personal information to third parties for commercial gain.  ****We will never give, lease, sell or otherwise disclose your personal information to third parties, other than for the specific purposes outlined below.  **

We understand that making purchases online involves a great deal of trust on your part; we take this trust very seriously, and make it our highest priority to ensure the security and confidentiality of the personal information you provide us. Any information you give to HealthPost will be held with the utmost care.

A more detailed explanation of how we safeguard your personal information is found below.  This should be read in conjunction with our [Terms & Conditions](https://www.healthpost.co.nz/customer-service/terms-conditions "Terms & Conditions").

If you've any questions or concerns, [please let us know.](https://www.healthpost.co.nz/contacts "Contact us") We're always happy to help.

HealthPost is proud to have been awarded to the international Online Trust Alliance (OTA) [‘2014 Online Trust Honour Roll’](https://www.healthpost.co.nz/customer-service/privacy-security/2014-online-trust-honour-roll "2014 Online Trust Honour Roll") for New Zealand.

* * *

## The Long Version

#### **Introduction**

www.healthpost.co.nz (“this website”) is operated by HealthPost Ltd. (“we”, “us”, “our”), a New Zealand registered company.

**We respect the privacy of our website users (“you”, “your”) and are committed to protecting your security and privacy.**

#### **Terms of Use**

This privacy policy must be read in conjunction with our Terms and Conditions.

#### **Collection of Your Information**

We collect information about you through our website in an effort to improve your shopping experience, as well as communicate with you about our products, services and promotions. **We do not sell or rent your personal information to third parties for commercial gain.**

We will generally never give, lease, sell or otherwise disclose your personal information to any third parties except to comply with law; facilitate court proceedings; enforce our Terms & Conditions; or protect the rights, property, or safety of HealthPost Ltd, our users, or others. We may however share or store your email address and other basic information with our third party business partners including marketing, advertising and research companies and data analysis companies.  We do this in order to conduct sales, marketing and advertising research and analysis on our behalf so that we can: better understand your preferences; improve the services we offer you; present you with suitable offers that you might be interested in. We will only do this with reputable organisations who are acting directly on our behalf to improve the services we offer you, and not for any other purpose (and certainly not to promote their own products and services directly to you). We also need to store your personal information within the hardware and software systems of reputable third parties in order to facilitate and improve the services which we offer. The privacy and data security policies and standards of the third party organisations we engage for these purposes will be subject to review by HealthPost, and required to meet high standards of care and responsibility.

We may be obliged to release account and other personal information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with law; facilitate court proceedings; enforce or apply our terms and conditions; or protect the rights, property, or safety of HealthPost Ltd, our users, or others.  To the extent we are legally permitted to do so, we will take reasonable steps to notify you in the event that we are required to provide your personal information to third parties as part of a legal process.

#### **Data Retention**

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, please [contact us](https://www.healthpost.co.nz/contacts "contact us"). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

#### **Types of Information Collected**

We may collect personal information from you (including, without limitation, your name, email address, phone number, address and purchase history) when you visit our website, register with our website, place an online order, save your information with us online, contact us with a question or concern, or participate in a promotion. This information is used to correspond with you, deliver products to you or fulfill any other aspect of our service, and communicate with you about our products and services, including marketing and promotional material.  

We also receive and collect the name of the domain and host from which you access the Internet; the Internet protocol (IP) address of the computer you are using; the browser software you use and your operating system; the date and time you access our site; and any search engine or inbound hyperlink used to reach this website which is made available to us. This information is used only for statistical purposes and in regards to how we may enhance the customer experience.

#### **Access to Your Information**

You have the right to access personal information about you and request corrections or updates to be made, provided we hold such information in a way that it can be readily accessed and amended.

#### **Email Communication**

Use of our website requires you to accept certain email communications from us, some of which you are required to receive in order for us to be able to fulfil our service, e.g. we send an 'order confirmation' email confirming that your order has been successfully placed.  We also send marketing and promotional emails from time to time, but these are optional and you will always be provided with a link to 'Unsubscribe' from any such emails.

#### **Cookies**

Our website uses "cookies," which are small data files that are stored on your computer when you visit a website. Cookies enable you to shop on our website and may be used in a variety of ways to enhance or personalize your online browsing and shopping experience. Cookies may be used to personalise your visits to this website, eliminate the need for you to repeatedly enter the same information, enable us to improve the content, reliability and functionality of this website, evaluate the effectiveness of the advertising on this website and track website usage patterns. We also use cookies for advertising purposes. 

We use three types of cookies:

  * _Session cookies_ are specific to your visit on our site and carry information about actions performed during the visit, e.g. products added to the cart. They eliminate the need to enter the same information repeatedly during your visit.  Session cookies expire when you leave the site or close your browser.

  * _Persistent cookies_ remember information about your preferences, e.g. your preferred currency and help us recognise you each time you visit to make your shopping experience more seamless. Persistent cookies expire after a certain period of time or when you clear cookies in your browser.  

  * _Third-party cookies_ are cookies supplied by our partners and are used for analytical and advertising purposes. While these cookies are completely anonymous in that they don’t provide us or any third party with any personally identifiable information about you (e.g. your name or address), it does track certain things like how long you spent on our site, and which pages you did or didn't visit. This allows us to use Remarketing functionality as described below and analyze aggregated traffic data and users behaviour on our site.

Accepting a cookie will not give us access to any data on your computer other than the data stored in the cookie. Although you may configure your web browser to not accept cookies, you may experience a loss of functionality as a result. If you wish to clear your cookies, follow instructions for the browser you're using: [Chrome](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en), [Firefox](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/cookies-information-websites-store-on-your-computer), [Safari](https://support.apple.com/kb/ph21411?locale=en_NZ), [Microsoft Edge](https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy), [Microsoft Explorer](https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies).

#### **Third-Party Remarketing**

When you visit our website with cookies enabled, we place a third party cookie supplied by Google, Facebook, Criteo or other partners onto your browser for remarketing purposes. For example, if you visited a particular product, we might use this information to display advertising to you promoting a special offer specific to this product. This advertising may be displayed to you as you browse other sites across the internet. This is possible because many websites participate in third-party's advertising programme, allowing them to use parts of their sites to display promotional messages from participating advertisers. You may also see our advertisements on sites directly owned or controlled by Google, such as Youtube or on Facebook.

You may opt out of Google's use of cookies for advertising at [www.google.com/settings/ads](http://www.google.com/settings/ads "Google Ads Settings"). You may opt out of Criteo's use of cookies for advertising at [www.criteo.com/privacy](http://www.criteo.com/privacy/ "Criteo Settings"). To manage your Facebook preferences go to: [www.facebook.com/ads/preferences](https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/). 

We might also use personal identifiers (such as email address) to display our ads to you on Facebook. If you wish to opt out from being targeted on Facebook by use of personal identifiers please [contact us](https://www.healthpost.co.nz/contacts). 

#### **How we use Your Information**

We may use your collected information in the following ways:

  * To process and fulfil your order, including sending emails to confirm your order status and shipment, along with customary business communications.
  * To verify your identity and to assist you if you have forgotten your username or password
  * To communicate with you and to send you information by email, postal mail or other means about our products, services and promotions, where you agree to receive such information.
  * To help us learn more about your shopping preferences and personalise our offer to you in accordance with your preferences.
  * To analyze trends and statistics.
  * To improve or update this website and our products / services.
  * To protect the security or integrity of our website and our business.
  * To respond to your enquiries and communicate with you if necessary.

You always have the choice not to receive marketing and promotional information. It is our policy to remove any member from our database or mailing list upon the members’ request. Please [contact us](https://www.healthpost.co.nz/contacts "contact us") if you wish to opt out of receiving marketing communications from HealthPost Ltd.

#### **Business Continuity**

In the event that HealthPost’s business is acquired or merged or in the unlikely event HealthPost Ltd goes out of business enters into liquidation or receivership. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of HealthPost Ltd may continue to use the information collected by HealthPost.

#### **Website and Credit Card Security**

**We take website and credit card security extremely seriously.**

HealthPost endeavour to provide a safe and secure platform on which to conduct online transactions. www.healthpost.co.nz uses the industry standard Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol, which encrypts your personal information as it is transmitted over the internet. This encryption scrambles details such as your password and address so that generally, other computers are unable to decipher the information, ensuring privacy and security. To make sure you are accessing a secure server, check for a closed padlock symbol in your browser window.  In the latest versions of the Chrome and Firefox browsers, this appears before the URL itself in the browswer address bar, in Internet Explorer it's shown to the right of the address. If this appears, then SSL is active. You can double check this by looking at the URL as well. If SSL is active, then the first characters of that line will read ‘https’ rather than just ‘http’. It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer.

No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

Please ensure you sign out when you have finished visiting www.healthpost.co.nz, especially if you access our website from a shared computer.

We use Payment Express to process all credit card payments. For more info, please refer to their [privacy policy.  
](http://www.paymentexpress.com/about/about_paymentexpress/privacy_policy.html)

[  
](http://www.paymentexpress.com/about/about_paymentexpress/privacy_policy.html)

#### **Linking to Third-Party Websites**

When you click on links and banners on our site that take you to third party web sites, you will be subject to the third party's privacy policies. While we support the protection of privacy on the Internet, HealthPost Ltd cannot be responsible for the actions of any third-party web sites.

#### **Product Reviews**

We reserve the right to use all product reviews we receive in our marketing and promotional material, both on and offline, identifying reviewers by first name only. If you don't want us to use your review, please let us know.

#### **Changes to our Privacy Policy**

We reserve the right to change this privacy policy from time to time by publishing the revised privacy policy on our website. We encourage you to check this policy regularly for any modifications or updates. Your continued use of our Services after any changes have been posted on our Website indicates your acceptance of those changes.

If you have any questions regarding our privacy policy or any other matter, or if you believe that HealthPost has not adhered to this privacy policy, please [contact us](https://www.healthpost.co.nz/contacts "contact us").  We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem.
